Tyler T. Mullen

Email: T_mullen93@yahoo.com | Phone: 612-644-7902 | Address: 8916 Northwood Parkway, New Hope, MN

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyler-mullen-94905553/ GitHub: https://github.com/RatofWrath |

Website: https://ratofwrath.github.io/Responsive-Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Web developer with a bachelor's degree in computer science as well as experience coding sorting algorithms and a compiler for mini-pascal using Java. Currently enrolled in a boot camp for full stack development with MERN. Experienced in teaching end-users how to use technologies and working in fast-paced environments with demanding deadlines that require communication with co-workers and clients. Looking forward to utilizing my expertise in coding and troubleshooting to create web pages, applications and software.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient with using Java, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Node.js, Firebase, phpMyAdmin, API's and Git Bash.

PROJECTS

LIRI Search Bot | https://github.com/RatofWrath/liri-node-app

- Allows the user to run search for concert dates, movie info or song info.
- Uses spotify's API to search through spotify's database and axios to search bands-in-town and OMDB's database.
- Node.js, Moment, Spotify API, Axios, JavaScript

Train Scheduler https://github.com/RatofWrath/Train-Scheduler https://ratofwrath.github.io/Train-Scheduler/

- The user can add a train to a schedule which will display the name along with the next arrival.
- Sends data to and pull data from firebase in order display all scheduled trains.
- Firebase, Moment, JavaScript, CSS, HTML

Gridiron Greats Trivia Game | https://github.com/RatofWrath/TriviaGame | https://ratofwrath.github.io/TriviaGame/

- A six question football trivia game that the user has ninety seconds to complete.
- After the game is finished, a screen with the number of correct, incorrect and unanswered questions is displayed.
- JavaScript, CSS, HTML

Crystal Collectors Game https://github.com/RatofWrath/unit-4-game/
https://ratofwrath.github.io/unit-4-game/

- A game where 4 pictures can be clicked on and each gives a value of points that is hidden from the user. The user wins if they match a displayed number of points and loses if they go over.
- JavaScript, CSS, HTML

EXPERIENCE

Back of House Team Member – Chick-Fil-A – Bloomington, MN

2017 - Present

- Cultivating strong relationships with co-workers and demonstrating a calm composure, particularly when problems and busyness increase.
- Help oversee food safety by monitoring the temperature of all chicken and ensuring refrigerators are at an adequate temperature.
- First team member (out of 35) to complete a rigorous online training program set up by my franchise's operator.
- Trained co-workers on proper cleaning and maintenance of deep fryers.

Technical Consultant – Allina Health – Minneapolis, MN

2016 - 2017

- Assisted approximately fifty Allina Health patients per day by recovering login information, resetting passwords and changing account information upon request.
- Knowledgeable in Allina Health's patient portal, MyChart and explained features and benefits to patients.
- Created and processed sign-up forms for MyChart user login for new patients.

Intern – Lifeworks – Eagan, MN

June 2016 - August 2016

- Relocated and rewired approximately twenty computers during the facility's remodel/reorganization.
- Installed Windows 8 updates onto all computers.
- Managed the personal login updates for all 150+ staff members across six offices in Minnesota to ensure they would not be affected by a recent security breach.
- Grew in my ability to communicate with others and to execute the setup of IT equipment.

<u>Wait Staff</u> – Sholom Community Alliance – Saint Louis Park, MN

2011 - 2014

- Provided attentive service to senior residents by serving multi-course meals
- Assisted in pre and post-meal preparation and clean-up
- Aided impaired residents with basic meal assistance

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota, St. Paul, MN – Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

Augsburg College, Minneapolis, MN – B.A. In Computer Science